INDYA DODSON

T: 443-388-2668 | E: indya.i.dodson@gmail.com | G: github.com/iidodson

Summary

Versatile Software Engineer with proven capabilities in designing accessible user-centered experiences, developing websites, and managing products from end to end.

Skills

Programming: Python, Javascript, Java, SQL. HTML, CSS **Tech Stack**: React.js, Node.js, Angular JS, Express, MonogDB

Tools: Git, Jira, Sketch. Figma

Experience _

Product Analyst (Product Owner)

San Francisco, CA

Medrio Inc.

Jan 2019 - Dec 2019

- Created three core features in Medrio's Electronic Data Capture platform to meet the needs of 3,000 clinical trial patients.
- Launched a Serious Adverse Events notification system that was adopted by 45% of customers within its first month.
- Analyzed customer data using SQL to identify workflow improvement, leading to a 21% higher conversion rate.
- Developed low fidelity prototypes in HTML, CSS, and Javascript resulting in a 10% increase in product delivery time.
- Spearheaded the agile process with user research, user stories, sprint planning, demos, and retrospectives for three global scrum teams.

Technical Support Representative

San Francisco, CA

Medrio Inc.

Jun 2018 - Dec 2018

- Handled 15-25 telephone calls per day by providing technical support and troubleshooting for API and UI software issues.
- Authored and maintained over 20 technical specification guides resulting in a 50% decrease in new hire ramp-up time.
- Closed 1,000 support cases within 5 months of employment and maintained a CSAT score of 95%.
- Trained and mentored a team of four new hires on customer issues and best practices who maintained a cumulative CSAT score of 90%.

Software Engineer Intern

San Francisco, CA

UserTesting Inc.

May 2016 – Sept 2016

- Developed a front-end style guide in HTML, CSS, and Angular to maintain consistent product designs in a modular format.
- Collaborated cross-functionally to develop web pages that scaled and performed efficiently across several devices.
- Implemented 10 desktop and mobile interfaces that helped increase the scrum team's velocity by 20%.

Projects

Brain Controlled Interface (BCI) Drone

Capitol Technology University - GPA: 3.6/4.0

Laurel. MD

Python, Numpy

Dec 2017 - May 2018

- Developed an application in Python that paired concise drone movements to brain waves captured by an EEG.
- Processed EGG data using Numpy through a stream to extract spatial brain information resulting in a 68% accuracy rate.
- Analyzed results on a case by case basis to create a universal model that supported multiple users.

Education

Bachelors of Science in Computer Science - Cum Laude

Laurel. MD

May 2018

Coursework: Computer Algorithms. Operating Systems, Database Administration

Volunteer Experience